Yaser A. Al-Thahab

Phone: +44 7427338054

Portfolio Site: https://cv-site-yaser-ali.vercel.app/

LinkedIn Profile URL: https://www.linkedin.com/in/yaser-ali-17654a241/

Email: yaser.ali32@hotmail.co.uk

Education

2019 – 2020 Software Development B.S (Hons): Upper second (2:1) (67%)

Manchester Metropolitan University

2017 – 2019 Computing HNC / HND: Merit

UCEN Manchester

2014 – 2017 IT Computer Science OCR: Certificate

The Manchester College

Summary:

A well-presented, friendly, hardworking, and highly technical individual with a passion for technology, programming and, of course, development. I am a graduate who graduated with a strong upper second in software development. I am currently specializing, working, and developing applications for companies and organizations.

As a developer, I enjoy solving problems and developing substantial, quantitative, and readable code. But also, the way an application is developed such as its design, UI (User Interface), and functionality. I am comfortable working with an agile software development team and giving ideas for development practices.

Technical:

Proficient knowledge in PHP and Java, especially in many different programming languages and technologies such as node.js, Java, HTML5, React.js, vue.js, Python and C#. I do make extensive use of GIT and among other favourable software frameworks. I have been working on web applications during my adolescent years, but I also worked on a couple of software applications.

Employment

Mar 2021 - Sept 2021

Software Developer

Go Earth Ltd

- Developed a commercially viable database application with the use of MS Access and VBA.
- WordPress to create a responsive, mobile-friendly, and interactive website for a given project.
- Python to create a parsing tool to receive boat search details and information.

Aug 2020 - Mar 2021

IT Technician (Admin)

My-Places Ltd

- Fixing the software, hardware and IT issues that occurs periodically within the office.
- Using Wordpress for designing the website in detailed attention and in a great manner.
- Helping employees and the director's IT, hardware, or software issues outside and inside of working hours.

Dec 2019 - Feb 2020

Web developer

Lawbid

- Writing back-end scripting with the use of PHP and node.js to pre-register page as well as the other pages.
- Adding features and specialties to the website in terms of design, interactivity, and functionality.
- Implementing the site's functionality, interactivity, and style on each page such as profile page, dashboard, and other stylish pages with the use of react.js, angular.js, jQuery, Bootstrap as well as foundation for making the site responsive and agile.
- Using React Native for mobile-friendly usages and allowing clients and solicitors to communicate more easily on their mobiles and smartphones.
- Using git, bower and gulp.js for tracking changes in the site and code changes.

Sept 2017 - June 2019

Front end developer

Ourthing

- Creating games for clients and head-developer.
- Creating web pages for the clients and the head-developer.
- Testing the website, the website's games, finding out bugs, errors or anything and fix them according to the plan.
- Rewriting scripts and developing features into the site.

Licenses & Certifications:

IBM Machine Learning with Python – March 2020

Issuing Organization: Coursera License ID: RA3AD5HZYP35 Grade Achieved: 87%